// creating an array and passing the number, questions, options, and answers
let questions = [
  {
    numb: 1,
    question: "  Which of the following is the full form of DDL?",
    answer: " Data definition language.",
    options: [
      " Data definition language.",
      " Data defie language.",
      "  Data determinant language.",
      " Data dynamic language."
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 2,
    question: "Which of the following is generally used for performing tasks like creating the structure of the relations, deleting relation?",
    answer: " DDL(Data Definition Language)",
    options: [
      "DCL",
      "DML",
      "Relational Schem",
      "DDL(Data Definition Language)"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 3,
    question: "What do you mean by one to many relationships?",
    answer: "One teacher can have many classes",
    options: [
      "One teacher can have many classes",
      "Many classes may have many teachers",
      "One class may have many teachers",
      "None of the above"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 4,
    question: "A Database Management System is a type of _________software.",
    answer: " It is a type of system software",
    options: [
      " It is a type of system software",
      "  It is a kind of application software",
      "It is a kind of general software",
      "Both A and C"
    ]
  },


  {
    numb: 5,
    question: "Which of the following can be considered as the maximum size that is supported by FAT?",
    answer: "4GB",
    options: [
      "4GB",
      "14GB",
      "8GB",
      "6GB"
    ]
  },


  {
    numb: 6,
    question: "Which of the following can be used to extract or filter the data & information from the data warehouse?",
    answer: "Data mining",
    options: [
      "Data mining",
      "Data mining",
      "Cycle stealing",
      "Both B and C"
    ]
  }
,

  {
    numb: 7,
    question: "Which one of the following refers to the copies of the same data (or information) occupying the memory space at multiple places.",
    answer: "Data Redundancy",
    options: [
      "Data Repository",
      "Data stealing",
      " Data Mining",
      "Data Redundancy"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 8,
    question: "Rows of a relation are known as the _______. ",
    answer: "All of the above",
    options: [
      "All of the above",
      " Degree",
      "Tuples",
      "Entity"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 9,
    question: " Which of the following command is a type of Data Definition language command?",
    answer: "Create",
    options: [
      "Create",
      "Update",
      "Delete",
      "New"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 10,
    question: "In which one of the following, the multiple lower entities are grouped (or combined) together to form a single higher-level entity?",
    answer: "Generalization",
    options: [
      "Generalization",
      "Specialization",
      "Aggregation",
      "None of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 11,
    question: "Which of the following commands is used to save any transaction permanently into the database?",
    answer: " Commit",
    options: [
      "Commit",
      "New",
      "Savepoint",
      "None of the above"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 12,
    question: "Which of the following is used in the application programs to request data from the database management system?",
    answer: "Data Manipulation language",
    options: [
      "Data Manipulation language",
      "Data Definition Language",
      "Data Control Language",
      "None of the above"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 13,
    question: "The term 'SQL' stands for ",
    answer: "Structured query language",
    options: [
      "Standard query language",
      "Structured query language",
      "Standarded query language",
      "None of the above"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 14,
    question: " The architecture of a database can be viewed as the ________",
    answer: "Three-level",
    options: [
      "Three-level",
      "Two-level",
      "one-level",
      "five-level"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 15,
    question: "Which of the following keys is generally used to represents the relationships between the tables?",
    answer: "Foreign key",
    options: [
      "Foreign key",
      "Primary key",
      " Candidate key",
      "None of these"
    ]
  }
    
];